Zhijian Wen

Curriculum Vitae

Personal Summary

I am a graduate with Master major in Statistics, with experiences in data analysis/modelling, programming including developing **R**-package and data mining. I am interesting in programming and I am enjoying to "talk" with computer. I am keen to join your company where I want to utilize my skills in creative.

Education

2016–2017 Msc - Statistics, University of Auckland.

Key course: Multivariate Analysis, Data Science Practice, Statistical Inference

2015–2016 BSc(Hons) - Statistics, University of Auckland.

Key course: Bayesian Inference, Statistical Computing, Statistical Modelling class representation of **Stats 779**

2012–2015 BSc - Mathematics and Statistics, University of Auckland.

Projects

Master Emulate the persp plot and filled.contour plot in gridGraphics.

The persp() is use for drawing 3-D surface and the filled.contour() is use for drawing filled level contour plot in the **graphics**-package, which is the based package in **R**. My job is to convert (redraw) these two kinds of plot (functions) to **grid**. Supervisor: Associate Professor Paul Murrell

Honours Bayesian inference on forensic glass evidence.

The aim of this project is to fit a zero inflated poisson mixture model and zero inflated negative mixture model to different situations (e.g. The breaker's distance from the window, Proportion of high persistence fragments).

Supervisor: Professor James Curran

Work Experience

2016-2017 Teaching assistant, University of Auckland.

Tutor and Marker of Stats 220: This course introduces a variety of computer technologies relevant to storing, managing, and processing data. My job is to help students to understand and solve the questions about the coding. Such as HTML/CSS, SOL and R

Marker of Stats 380: A course of statistical computing using the R statistical computing environment

2015-2016 Summer Scholarship, University of Auckland.

Working on the iNZightMaps-package, used in the mapping module for **iNZight** I am one of the author of the iNZightMaps-package. I was working on the functions for plotting the geographical data and also made it handle coordinate and country data.

Skills

Advance: R, HTML, LATEX

Fair: SAS, SQL, jags, Linux, Lua, JavaScript

Basic: C, C++, JAON, XML, MATLAB, Excel

Languages

English, Mandarin, Cantonese

Interest

• Game Computing

Statistical Computing

o Table tennis

Physics

Lizzie Long 1 Short Street Middelsburgh Auckland 9999

30 July 2016

Reginald Farnham ABC Sales 85 Tuesday Road Papakura AUCKLAND 7777

Dear Reginald

Thank you for the opportunity to apply for the [Something] role at your company. After reviewing your job description, it is clear that your are looking for a candidate that is extremely familiar with the responsibilities associated with the role, and can perform them confidently. Given these requirements, I am certain that I have the necessary skills to successfully do the

job adeptly and perform above expectations.

I am a focused recent college graduate (Master of Statistics) from the University of Auckland. During the course of my academic career, I also managed to accrue nearly 2 years of work experience. I had the privilege of working for University of Auckland in a Teaching assistant role in my free time, where I learned valuable professional skill such as.... In both my academic and professional life, I have been consistently praised as efficient by my professors and peers. Whether working on academic, extracurricular, or professional projects, I apply proven technical,

research, and team work skills, which I hope to leverage into the [...] at your company.

After reviewing my resume, I hope you will agree that I am the type of competent and competitive candidate you are looking for. I look forward to elaborating on how my specific skills and abilities will benefit your organization.

Thank you for your consideration, and I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Sincerely,

Zhijian Wen